If you haven't already noticed, the text is kind of tiny on this device screen.
你可能沒有注意到 設備螢幕上的文字有一點小
I mean, my eyesight is terrible, so I really need it to be a lot bigger.
我的意思是 我的視力不好 因此我想讓文字變大一點
Luckily for us,
幸運的是
there is an attribute that we can declare to change the text size.
我們可以宣告一個屬性 來更改文字大小
Oh, but wait there is an error down here.
請等一會兒 這裏有一個錯誤
It says the computer wasn't able to understand my XML.
說電腦不能 理解我的XML
Double checking the code I see this new line that we added is actually appearing
再次檢查代碼後我發現 新增的這行代碼
in black font, whereas everything above has blue for
顯示為黑色字體 而在上面 屬性名稱
the attribute name and red for the attribute value.
顯示為藍色 屬性值顯示為紅色
So there's something wrong with this line.
因此 這行代碼 有問題
Oh wait, I see it now.
現在我看到了
Forward slash in the closing angle bracket are on this side up here.
右尖括號中的斜械 位於這一側
This is actually a common beginner mistake to add the attribute
這是新手經常會犯的錯誤 就是在括號封閉之後
after the tack has been closed.
增加屬性
Technically, this is hanging out in XML limbo or
從技術上說 這不符合XML語法規則
something because it's not tied to an XML element.
因為它沒有關聯到 一個XML元素
What we really want is to copy these symbols and move them down here.
我們需要做的是 複製這些符號 把它們移到這裏
That's better.
這樣好多了
There's no error, and this is valid XML, and then our font is bigger.
錯誤不見了 變成有效的XML 然後 我們的字體也變大了
Woo hoo!
哇
It's much more readable now.
這樣更容易識讀了
Note how the text size is set to be 45 sp.
請注意 現在文字大小 被設定為45sp
Sp stands for scale independent pixels.
Sp表示比例無關像素
It is a unit of measure similar to dp which makes the app look
它是一個測量單位 類似於dp 其作用是為了在不同像素密度的設備上
consistent across different devices of different densities.
保持相同的 顯示版面
Sp is only used for fonts because it adjusts based on the user's
Sp只用於字體 因為它根據 使用者的偏好
preferences and settings for text size.
和文字大小設定進行調整
Let's look at that now.
現在讓我們看一下
Let me show you where the setting is.
我們來看設定值在哪裏
Go to the settings app, then tap on display, and there's an option for
轉到設定應用程式 然後輕觸一下 顯示 這裏有一個
font size.
字體大小選項
If you click on that, you can see the different font sizes.
如果按一下這個選項 可以看到不同的字體大小
If I click on huge, and it increases the font size of everything.
如果我按一下巨大 就會增大所有內容的字體大小
So always use sp to declare your font sizes so it will scale up or
因此始終應使用sp宣告你的 字體大小 這樣它就會根據使用者的偏號
down according to the user's preference.
放大或縮小字體
In a moment you'll change the text size of the text view.
一會兒後 你將會更改文字檢視圖的 文字大小
However, I first wanted to show you one thing.
但是 我首先要向你展示 一個東西
This is the material design spec.
這是素材設計規范
Material design is a new design language developed by Google
素材設計是Google開發的 一種新設計語言
to help people create consistent and
幫助我們建立一致
beautiful apps across different devices and platforms, like web and mobile.
美觀的應用程式 可以跨越不同的設備 和平臺 比如Web和行動設備
The design specification, or design specs for
簡單地說 設計規范
short, highlights the best practices for designing your app.
是用於指導應用程式設計 的最佳做法
It provides guidance on the layout of your app, visual style, imagery,
它指導應用程式的版面 視覺樣式 圖像
animations, and much more.
動畫和其他元素
There's also a section on typography, or fonts.
還有一個章節介紹印刷格式 或字體
It lists a whole bunch of information here that you can read later.
它含有豐富的內容 你可以在以後詳細閱讀
But the most important thing is this guide here,
在這個指南中 最重要的事項是
that talks about the recommended text sizes.
建議文字大小
If you're displaying a really big header,
如果你要顯示 大字號標題
you can use some of these text size values.
可以使用其中 一些文字大小值
If you're trying to do a title or some body text or a caption,
如果要顯示正文文字 或標題
you can use some of these sizes.
可以使用這些大小值
This will help guide you on what types values you can pick depending on what
這幫助你根據使用情況 選擇合適
your use case is.
類型的值
But be careful, because if you pick too many type sizes or
但是請注意 如果你選擇 過多的類型大小
styles in your app, it can be very overwhelming for the user.
樣式 使用者將會 難以理解
So just pick a couple of styles to display the information that you want.
因此應選擇少數幾個樣式 來顯示你想要顯示的內容
When you change the text size for
當你更改TextView的
the TextView, try a couple of these values here.
文字大小時 請嘗試使用這裏的值
Go ahead and change the TextView font size using the material design spec.
請使用素材設計規范 更改TextView字體大小
And then if you're up for
如果遇到問題
a challenge, you can try learning about the text appearance attribute
可以在 Google+ Android Dev Protip中
from the Google+ Android Dev Protip that I've posted below.
查閱文字外觀屬性的相關訊息 我已經貼在下面
And then you can try this in the XML Visualizer as well.
然後 也可以在XML Visualizer中 嘗試這樣做
The link to the XML Visualizer with the code for
下面是XML Visualizer 和部分代碼的連結
you to get started is linked below.
將會對你有所幫助